<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-13T18:00:49-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dana Walker</title><subtitle>Data Science &amp; Product Analytics</subtitle><author><name>Dana Walker</name></author><entry><title type="html">Online Communities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/08/online-communities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online Communities" /><published>2023-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/08/communities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/08/online-communities/"><![CDATA[<p>There are so many online communities for women or anyone working in tech, analytics, data science, etc. Many have active Slack or Discord communities or local Chapters/Meetups.</p>

<p>A few that I’ve come across:</p>

<p>Women:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://dataangels.org/">Data Angels</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.widsconference.org/">WiDS</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://wimlds.org/">WiMLDS</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://pyladies.com/">PyLadies</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://rladies.org/">R-Ladies</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.womeninanalytics.com/">Women in Analytics</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Data:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://datatalks.club">DataTalks.Club</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://locallyoptimistic.com">Locally Optimistic</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://info.datascience.salon/apply-to-dss-slack-workspace">Data Science Salon</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.datavisualizationsociety.org">Data Visualization Society</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://academicdatascience.org/">Academic Data Science Alliance</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Aspiring Data Folks:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://dataxp.webflow.io/">DataXP</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://discord.com/invite/qtqF5YbArd">Analytics Mentor</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Chicago:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.chicagotechslack.com/">Chicago Tech</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.chipy.org/">Chicago Python Users Group</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/groups/14156219/">Chicago Data Community</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Dana Walker</name></author><category term="community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are so many online communities for women or anyone working in tech, analytics, data science, etc. Many have active Slack or Discord communities or local Chapters/Meetups.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/my-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Journey" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/my-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2021/12/my-journey/"><![CDATA[<p>Winding up in a data science career is both expected and a surprise to me. Let me explain.</p>

<p>During grammar school and high school, I was always good at math, scoring well in the most advaced courses offered, participating in Mathletes, and quickly picking up what little coding I was exposed to. When I learned HTML (in the 1990s), I was found it so fascinating that a few lines of code could allow me to communicate with seemingly the entire world. I hoped to have a career as a Webmaster.</p>

<p>I started college with plans to major in Computer Science. I found my first class extremely challenging and wound up very intimidated and unsure if this was the right career path for me. I decided that I wanted a more glamorous career.</p>

<p>I switched my major to Communication with the hope of working in Public Relations. But as I learned quickly after graduation, most jobs in PR are in pretty unglamorous industries. I also realized I didn’t enjoy the work that was typical for a role in PR or marketing communication.</p>

<p>However, I had no idea what else to do. I took some classes in the hopes of figuring out a better career path. First graphic design, but had similar feelings as I did with marketing/PR. I considered a career in engineering, and took Calculus, refreshing what I learned in college. I thoroughly enjoyed studying math again, but wasn’t sure I wanted to quit my full-time job and start over from square one with a second bachelors in civil engingeering. Data Science was not yet on my radar as it had not yet been named the “sexiest career of the 21st Century.” I didn’t come into contact with any analysts or statisticians at work, so those didn’t register as a career option.</p>

<p>Eventually, I transitioned to digital marketing, and with that came some data analysis, mostly web and social media data. I loved being able to “do math” at work. I learned as much as I could on the job so that I could get the most insight out of what little data was available. That was recognized, and eventually, during a team reorganization, I was moved into a role focused 100% on marketing analytics.</p>

<p>Luckily, I was working under someone with experience in that area, who exposed me to what I didn’t know about the world of analytics, statistics, and programs like R and Power BI. Learning R reminded me that I liked writing code and that a few lines of code could be so powerful.</p>

<p>I was fascinated with everything about analytics and I wanted to learn more. I was much more excited by this type of work than I ever was about PR or marketing.</p>

<p>Eventually, I realized if I wanted to move up in the area of analytics, I had a lot of skill gaps to cover. A liberal arts degree focused on Communication does not prepare you for quantitative analysis. To that end, I enrolled in a Master of Science in Data Science program, while continuing to work full-time.</p>

<p>So, in the end, despite my best efforts, I still ended up in a career that combined my math skills and interest in coding. The upside of my detour into communication, public relations, and marketing is that I was able to significantly improve my communication skills, which probably would not have happened had I followed my original path starting with Computer Science.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dana Walker</name></author><category term="about me" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winding up in a data science career is both expected and a surprise to me. Let me explain.]]></summary></entry></feed>